Guide to the Henry Draper Image Collection MC.230
New York University Archives
- Series III: Moon Images
  - July 24, 1872 30 sec exposure, cuid14871 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Aug 5, 1872 (5) 10-40 sec exposure, cuid14872 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Aug 18, 1872 10 sec exposure, cuid14873 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Moon, circa late 19th century; cuid14558; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, circa late 19th century; cuid14889; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, 17 August 1862; cuid14890; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, 16 August 1862; cuid14891; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Moon, circa late 19th century; cuid14892; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Observatories and Laboratories
  - Draper Domes at Harvard College Observatory (2), c. 1896; cuid14559; Glass plate and negative (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Naval Observatory (3), undated; cuid14560; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Naval Observatory (4), undated; cuid14561; Glass plate (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 8" Draper Camera at the Harvard College Observatory (6), c. 1898; cuid14562; Negative (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Draper's Clark Refractor Installed at Harvard College (7), c. 1896; cuid14563; Negative (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Draper's laboratory (1), undated; cuid14565; Glass plate (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Draper's laboratory (2), undated; cuid14566; Photographic print, copy of image (1) in this box. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Draper's laboratory equipment (3), undated; cuid14567; Glass plate (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Draper's laboratory equipment (4), undated; cuid14568; Glass plate (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Draper's laboratory equipment (5), undated; cuid14569; Glass plate (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Draper's laboratory equipment (6), undated; cuid14570; Glass plate (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (1), undated; cuid14571; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (2), undated; cuid14572; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (3), undated; cuid14573; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (4), undated; cuid14574; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (5), undated; cuid14575; Glass plate (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Telescope at Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (1), undated; cuid14576; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Heliostat at Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (3), undated; cuid14577; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Machinery (15), undated; cuid14578; Glass plate negative (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Draper's Hastings-on-Hudson Observatory (16), undated; cuid14579; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Train Station (17), undated; cuid14580; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - From Draper's laboratory-person probably not Draper (18), undated; cuid14581; Glass plate negative (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Draper Domes and telescope from south of observatory (Harvard), 1897; cuid14875 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Lantern slide, broken.
- Series V: NYU
  - NYU Exhibit at Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (1), 1893; cuid14582; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit at Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (2), 1893; cuid14583; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit at Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (3), 1893; cuid14584; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus Model (4), 1890s; cuid14585; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (6), 1890s; cuid14587; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (7), 1890s; cuid14588; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (8), 1890s; cuid14589; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit at Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (9), 1893; cuid14590; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit at Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (10), 1893; cuid14591; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit in Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (11), 1893; cuid14592; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Exhibit in Chicago, by C.L. Bristol (12), 1893; cuid14593; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus Model (13), 1890s; cuid14594; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (14), 1890s; cuid14595; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (15), 1890s; cuid14596; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (16), 1890s; cuid14597; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Campus (17), 1890s; cuid14598; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Main Building (18), 1894; cuid14599; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - NYU Main Building (19), 1894; cuid14600; Glass plate (Box 9)
  - Unidentified Group of Men (29), undated; cuid14601; Glass plate (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Heights Neighborhood-New Central Bridge, Haven River and 155th (1), undated; cuid14602; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-Valley at Harlem (2), undated; cuid14603; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-Railroad, Station, and Street Scene (3), undated; cuid14604; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-New government ship canal connecting Harlem and Hudson Rivers (4), undated; cuid14605; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-Bridge over river with Kessell's Manhattan Par(lor?) and Lion Brewery (5), undated; cuid14606; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-Bridge construction with workmen in foreground (6), undated; cuid14607; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Heights Neighborhood-Bridge/road with horse and carriage in foreground (7), undated; cuid14608; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Class in surveying-University Heights Grounds-shadow of cameraman in foreground (8), c. 1895; cuid14609; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - University Heights Biological Lab (9), c. 1895; cuid14610; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Class in surveying engineering (10), undated; cuid14611; Glass plate (Box 13)
  - Students on steps outside Gould Memorial Library "During Chapel Hour" from page 88 of the 1914 Violet (1), 1913; cuid14612; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Class Day at the Heights Campus (2), c. 1913; cuid14613; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Chemistry Lab from page 228 of the 1914 Violet, 1913; cuid14614; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (4), undated; cuid14615; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (5), undated; cuid14616; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (6), undated; cuid14617; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - NYU Ironwork-Guggenheim Lab (7), 9 July 1926; cuid14618; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (8), undated; cuid14619; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (9), undated; cuid14620; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (10), undated; cuid14621; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (11), undated; cuid14622; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (12), undated; cuid14623; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (13), undated; cuid14624; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (14), undated; cuid14625; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (15), undated; cuid14626; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (16), undated; cuid14627; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (17), undated; cuid14628; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (18), undated; cuid14629; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - Student Life (19), undated; cuid14630; Glass plate (Box 14)
  - 8 portraits of a woman, undated; cuid14631; Glass plate (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Educational Presentation Material
  - Solar spectrum (1), undated; cuid14632; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Solar spectrum (2), undated; cuid14633; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Moon-possible copy of Draper's original (3), 15 June; cuid14634; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Moon (4), undated; cuid14635; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Moon (5), undated; cuid14636; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Moon-possible copy of Draper's original (6), 22 June; cuid14637; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Mars-Schiaparelli (7), undated; cuid14638; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Parallax (8), undated; cuid14639; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Coincidence of the spectrum of iron (9), undated; cuid14640; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Astronomy (10), undated; cuid14641; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Telescope (11), undated; cuid14642; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Telescope (12), undated; cuid14643; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Living Room (13), undated; cuid14644; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Harvard College Observatory Arequipa Station (14), undated; cuid14645; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Harvard College Observatory Arequipa Station (15), undated; cuid14646; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Hot Springs, Isle Ngau (16), undated; cuid14647; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Jungle landscape (17), undated; cuid14648; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Siberian Landscape (18), undated; cuid14649; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Cityscape (19), undated; cuid14650; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Cityscape (20), undated; cuid14651; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Cityscape (21), undated; cuid14652; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Landscape (22), undated; cuid14653; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Mountain Range (23), undated; cuid14654; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Bridge (24), undated; cuid14655; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Pine Hill Highway Bridge (25), 1897; cuid14656; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Johnstown ruins-smoking buildings (26), undated; cuid14657; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Johnstown ruins-ruins of houses (27), undated; cuid14658; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Johnstown ruins-Ottenad Furniture at Broadway and Soulard (28), undated; cuid14659; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Johnstown ruins-Fourth Street and Choteau Avenue (29), undated; cuid14660; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Niagara Falls-American side (30), undated; cuid14661; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Covered walkway (31), undated; cuid14662; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Ideal Geological Landcape-5 Forest of Coal Period (32), undated; cuid14663; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Insect specimens (33), undated; cuid14664; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Nerves (34), undated; cuid14665; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Room's reflection on a sphere (35), undated; cuid14666; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of frog with piece of lead in thorax (36), 1896; cuid14667; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Lead pencil, steel calipers, fountain pen (37), 1896; cuid14668; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Clam shell (38), 1896; cuid14669; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Disc of lead (39), 1896; cuid14670; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of steel gauge in Morocco case and metal badge in round wooden box (40), 1896; cuid14671; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of steel gauge in Morocco case and other objects (41), 1896; cuid14672; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of knife, small carbon pencil, chalk, crayon, and dropper (42), 1896; cuid14673; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Photographic action of radium A over circular gauge and radium B over rectangular gauge (43), 1900; cuid14674; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of steel gauge in Morocco case and other objects (44), 1896; cuid14675; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of two sheets of strip lead (45), undated; cuid14676; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of steel calipers enclosed in wooden box and keys outside of box (46), 1896; cuid14677; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of 6 month old child (47), undated; cuid14678; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Radiograph of a leg (48), undated; cuid14679; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Taking radiograph at NYU (49), 1896; cuid14680; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - X-ray outfit at NYU (50), undated; cuid14681; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (51), undated; cuid14682; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (52), undated; cuid14683; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (53), undated; cuid14684; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (54), undated; cuid14685; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (55), undated; cuid14686; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Early solar spectrum (56), undated; cuid14687; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum (57), c. 1870; cuid14688; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum (58), c. 1870; cuid14689; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum of CuNO5 (59), c. 1870; cuid14690; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum of tin and mercury (60), c. 1870; cuid14691; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum of magnesium (61), c. 1870; cuid14692; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Laboratory spectrum of platinum (62), c. 1870; cuid14693; Lantern slide (Box 31)
  - Moon (63), 27 August 1863; cuid14694; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (64), 16 September 1864; cuid14695; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (65), 15 October 1864; cuid14696; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (66), 28 August 1863; cuid14697; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (67), 4 August 1863; cuid14698; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (68), 19 June 1864; cuid14699; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (69), 3 August 1863; cuid14700; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (70), 15 June 1864; cuid14701; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (71), 30 August 1863; cuid14702; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (72), 30 August 1863; cuid14703; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (73), 3 August 1863; cuid14704; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (74), 3 August 1863; cuid14705; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (75), 27 August 1863; cuid14706; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (76), 18 October 1864; cuid14707; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (77), 30 August 1863; cuid14708; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (78), 13 October 1864; cuid14709; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (79), 15 October 1864; cuid14710; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (80), 25 August 1864; cuid14711; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (81), 21 June 1864; cuid14712; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (82), 16 June 1864; cuid14713; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (83), 2 September 1863; cuid14714; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (84), 22 June 1864; cuid14715; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (85), 12 June 1864; cuid14716; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (86), 22 June 1864; cuid14717; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (87), 22 June 1864; cuid14718; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (88), 22 June 1864; cuid14719; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (89), 23 June 1864; cuid14720; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (90), August 1864; cuid14721; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (91), August-September 1864; cuid14722; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (92), 25 June 1864; cuid14723; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (93), 14 September 1864; cuid14724; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (94), 17 September 1864; cuid14725; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (95), August-September 1864; cuid14726; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon (96), 17 September 1864; cuid14727; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Colored spectra (97), cuid14728; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Colored spectra of a star (98), 18 February 1869; cuid14729; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sun? (99), undated; cuid14730; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sun (100), undated; cuid14731; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sun (101), undated; cuid14732; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sun (102), undated; cuid14733; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (103), undated; cuid14734; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (104), undated; cuid14735; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Empty slide (105), undated; cuid14736; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Moon-possible copy at about 1 1/2 enl. (106), undated; cuid14737; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (107), undated; cuid14738; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk D.T.G. (108), undated; cuid14739; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (109), undated; cuid14740; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (110), undated; cuid14741; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar disk (111), undated; cuid14742; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar image (112), undated; cuid14743; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - "Painted" spectrum (113), undated; cuid14744; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Empty slide (114), undated; cuid14745; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - "Painted" spectra (115), undated; cuid14746; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - "Painted" spectra (116), undated; cuid14747; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - "Painted" spectra (117), undated; cuid14748; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sunspots (118), undated; cuid14749; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Sunspots (119), undated; cuid14750; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Pair of optical slits (120), undated; cuid14751; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Pair of optical slits (121), undated; cuid14752; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Wavelength scale (122), undated; cuid14753; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Mask with set of slits (123), undated; cuid14754; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar spectra (124), 1873; cuid14755; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar spectra (125), 1873; cuid14756; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar spectra (126), 1873; cuid14757; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - Solar spectra (127), 1873; cuid14758; Lantern slide (Box 32)
  - James Prescott Joule portrait (1), undated; cuid14759; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - James Prescott Joule's early apparatus (2), undated; cuid14760; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - James Prescott Joule's later apparatus (3), undated; cuid14761; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Rowland's apparatus (4), undated; cuid14762; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Two painted cats and moon (5), undated; cuid14763; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (6), undated; cuid14764; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (7), undated; cuid14765; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (8), undated; cuid14766; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Mg? with plate of glass in rays? (9), undated; cuid14767; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (10), undated; cuid14768; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (11), undated; cuid14769; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Drawing of solar prominences (12), undated; cuid14770; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Spectrum (13), undated; cuid14771; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Chart of Pleicedes showing nebula around stars taken with 8 inch telescope (14), undated; cuid14772; Lantern slide (Box 33)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897.
  - Spectra (15), undated; cuid14773; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Bl. lines Argus (16), undated; cuid14774; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Nova Aurigae (17), 1890-1891; cuid14775; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - 434 (18), undated; cuid14776; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Nova Normae and Nova Aurigae spectra (19), undated; cuid14777; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - No. D3258 - New variable in Scorpius (20), undated; cuid14778; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Cluster in Centauri (21), undated; cuid14779; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - AZ 31 - New variable in Scorpius (22), undated; cuid14780; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - AZ 30 - Nova Normae (23), 1893-1899; cuid14781; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - AZ 29 - Nova Normae (24), 1893; cuid14782; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - D3091 - The Southern Cross (25), undated; cuid14783; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Spectra of Alpha Canis Majoris, Alpha Canis Minoris, and Alpha Aurigae (26), undated; cuid14784; Lantern slide (Box 33)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Four prisms enlarged about thrice.
  - Spectra of Alpha Lyrae, Alpha Cygni, and Alpha Bootis (27), undated; cuid14785; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae (28), undated; cuid14786; Lantern slide (Box 33)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae at full light time and at minimum. The difference in width of the lines. The disappearance of 1 line at minimum and the overlapping of the ends of the spectra may be real phenomena and require further study. A number of plates taken last night will probably settle these points. The other spectra represent the variables Beta Lyrae and Omicron Ceti. The differences in these types of variables is well shown by these spectra. One prism (?) enlarged three times.
  - Spectra of Alpha Cassiopeii, P. Cygni, and H.P. 1311 (29), undated; cuid14787; Lantern slide (Box 33)
    Samples sent to Mrs. Draper December 23 1889.
  - Art history (30), undated; cuid14788; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (31), undated; cuid14789; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (32), undated; cuid14790; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (33), undated; cuid14791; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (34), undated; cuid14792; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (35), undated; cuid14793; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (36), undated; cuid14794; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (37), undated; cuid14795; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (38), undated; cuid14796; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (39), undated; cuid14797; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (40), undated; cuid14798; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (41), undated; cuid14799; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (42), undated; cuid14800; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (43), undated; cuid14801; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (44), undated; cuid14802; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (45), undated; cuid14803; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (46), undated; cuid14804; Lantern slide (Box 33)
  - Art history (47), undated; cuid14805; Lantern slide (Box 33)
- Series VII: Daguerreotypes
  - 24 blanks for daguerreotypes, undated; cuid14806 (Box 15)
    General
    Daguerreotype plates
  - Faint circular image, 1860; cuid14807; Daguerreotype plate (Box 35)
  - Cornelius Mathews, undated; cuid14808; Daguerreotype (Box 36)
  - Daguerreotype glass cover, 19th century; cuid14870 (Box 10)
- Series VIII: Fragments
  - Draper's physical laboratory behind his home at Wooster Street, NYC, undated; cuid14810; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14811; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14812; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14813; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14814; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14815; Glass plate fragments (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Founders Monument, circa 1900; cuid14817; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14816; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14818; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14819; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14820; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14821; Glass plate fragments (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14822; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14823; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14824; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14825; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14826; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14827; Glass plate fragments (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14828; Glass plate fragments (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14829; Glass plate fragments (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14830; Glass plate fragments (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, 3 April 1877; cuid14832; Glass plate fragments (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14831; Glass plate fragments (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Fragment 36, undated; cuid14833; Glass plate fragments (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Draper's home in New York or Naval Observatory in Washington, undated; cuid14834; Glass plate fragments (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Fragment, undated; cuid14835; Glass plate fragments (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14836; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14837; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14838; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14839; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14840; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14841; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14842; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14843; Glass plate fragments (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14844; Glass plate fragments (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14845; Glass plate fragments (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14846; Glass plate fragments (Box 23, Folder 2)